迈克 · 诺斯: 这部分特别有趣，超载签名。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: This part is particularly
interesting, overload signatures.
我们有一个函数叫 contactPeople。
So we have a function here
called contactPeople.
我接受了一个叫做方法的论点
And I take in an argument
called method and
这里的方法类型是字符串电子邮件或字符串电话。
the type of method here is either
the string email or the string phone.
然后接下来的任何其他参数可以是 HasEmail 或 HasPhone。
And then any other parameter that follows
can be either HasEmail or HasPhone.
和我们上次练习中使用的类型相同。
The same types that we were
using in the last exercise.
所以在这里，让我们确保这个工程，如我们所期望的那样。
So down here, let's make sure
that this works as we'd expect.
如果我想通过电子邮件联系别人，我可以这样做，那是无效的电子邮件地址。
If I wanna contact people by email, I can
do this, and that's invalid email address.
但是从类型的角度来看，它应该有用，这也有用。
But from a type perspective,
it should work, this also works.
这不应该有效，对吧，电子邮件，我的意思是，从概念上来说，这没有意义。
This should not work, right, email,
I mean, conceptually, this makes no sense.
如果我想给某人发邮件而他们只有一个电话号码,
If I'm trying to email someone and
they only have a phone number,
我们会遇到麻烦的。
we're gonna run into a problem.
不幸的是，这种方法目前是有效的。
And unfortunately, this currently works.
原因是我们定义了两个独立的
And the reason is we have
defined two independent and
不相关的约束。
unrelated constraints here.
它可以是电子邮件或电话，字符串，然后对象，我们
It can be either email or phone,
the string, and then the objects that we
可以是一个混合包的联系人与电子邮件和电话号码。
take can be sort of a mixed bag of
contacts with emails and phone numbers.
所以尽管这些是我们能找到的最窄的类型
So although these
are the narrowest types we could
为了完成我们需要完成的工作，我们需要提供这两个参数。
provide for these two arguments in order
to get done what we need to get done.
有一些不允许的组合，我们要防止。
There is some disallowed combination
that we want to prevent.
而 TypeScript 提供了一种实现这一点的方法。
And TypeScript provides
a way of doing this.
所以我想在这里看一个工具提示，contactPeople，和
So I wanna look at a tool tip here,
contactPeople, and
这和我们上面看到的完全吻合，对吗？
this matches exactly what
we're seeing above, right?
第一个参数是我们的两个特殊字符串之一。
The first argument is one
of our two special strings.
然后这是我们混合的 HasEmail 和 HasPhoneNumber。
And then this is our mixed bag
of HasEmail and HasPhoneNumber.
我要做的是创建两个额外的函数签名,
What I wanna do is create two
additional function signatures,
抱歉刚才那一跳。
sorry for that little jump there.
这些都是访问这个函数的特定有效方法。
And these are specific valid
ways to access this function.
所以第一个，你只能传递一封邮件，然后
So the first one,
you can only pass an email, and
那你必须给我一份有电子邮件地址的名单。
then you must give me a list of
people with email addresses.
第二个，只有电话，然后，只有电话号码。
Second one, only phone, and
then, only HasPhoneNumber.
如果我们现在看一下我们的工具提示，看到2中的1和2中的2了吗？
If we look at our tool tip now,
see that little 1 of 2 and 2 of 2?
我们可以通过两种方式调用这个函数,
There are two specific ways that
we can invoke this function,
要么指定字符串电子邮件，并给我的对象与电子邮件地址。
either specify the string email and
give me objects with an email address.
或者让我们用字符串 phone 和 HasPhoneNumber 连接。
Or let's get a line with the string
phone and HasPhoneNumber.
如果我们看看第三个有问题的例子,
And if we look at our third and
problematic example here,
它告诉我们，我们已经提供了一个物体的电话号码。
it's telling us that we've provided
an object with the phone number.
所以我要么改变一件事，要么改变另一件事，对吗？
So this either I have to change
one thing or the other, right?
它目前的错误是说，你必须使这个字符串电话,
It's currently erroring by saying,
you gotta make this string phone,
你在用别人的电话号码做手术。
you're operating on
people's phone numbers.
我没有电子邮件地址，所以，迈克 · 诺斯: 注意，我们
I don't have email addresses, so,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Note that we
有两种方法访问这个函数。
have two ways to access this function.
这些就是我们在这里定义的特定函数签名。
And those are the specific function
signatures we've defined up here.
这不是从外部调用的。
This is not callable from the outside.
只需要足够宽,
It just needs to be wide enough,
足够容纳所有的函数签名。
general enough to accommodate
all of the function signatures.
所以如果我移除这个，我们会在
So if I were to remove this,
we'd run into an error on
电话信号显示
the phone signature saying the underlying
实现不容许传递电话作为第一个参数。
implementation does not accommodate
passing phone as the first parameter.
所以它必须足够通用，以满足所有签名的需要
So it just has to be general enough that
it'll meet the needs of all signatures
在它上面。
above it.
迈克 · 诺斯: 什么事？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Yes?
扬声器2: 所以你可以安全地将类型签名从
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So could you just
safely remove the type signature from
实际的函数调用？
the actual function call?
迈克 · 诺斯: 这取决于你所说的安全。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: It depends
what you mean by safely.
所以你仍然可以从外部世界的角度,
So you could still,
like from the outside world's perspective,
就像现在一样安全。
it would be exactly as
safe as it is right now.
我认为你在这里说的基本上是
And I think what you're
saying here is basically
字符串，迈克诺斯: 和
string,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And
这是一个 anys 数组，对吗？
make this an array of anys, right?
演讲者2: 或者干脆把所有东西都拿走,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Or
even just removing everything,
53到56行的所有类型。
all the types from line 53 to 56.
因为我们已经拿到了49号和50号的申报单。
Cuz we've got the declarations on 49 and
50.
迈克 · 诺斯: 完全正确，这就是我们所说的隐式 anys。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Totally, and these would
become what we call implicit anys.
这是一个 anys 数组，这是一个 any。
So this is gonna be an array of anys,
this is gonna be an any.
从外面的世界，因为我们实际上不能访问的签名,
And from the outside world, because we
can't actually access the signature,
外部世界的类型检查永远不会与这个签名相比较。
no type checking from the outside world
ever is compared against this signature.
所以外面的世界并不关心，但是在这个功能里面,
So the outside world don't care,
but within this function,
我现在身处西部荒野。
I'm in the Wild West here.
在函数中，我没有任何类型安全。
Within the function,
I don't have any kind of type safety.
所以这是一个好主意
So it's a good idea for
保持这个功能的目的不是超级，超级一般。
the purpose of maintaining this function
to not be super, super general.
你可能会这么做,
You might do something like this,
特别是如果你最终创造了一大堆这样的签名。
especially if you end up creating
a whole bunch of these signatures here.
比如说，我们有传真、短信和烟雾信号。
Like let's say, we had fax and
SMS and smoke signal.
它开始到达一个点，这成为一个困难的管理类型。
And it starts to get to a point where
this becomes a difficult to manage type.
我可能会退回到字符串这里，对吧？
And I might fall back to string here,
right?
迈克 · 诺斯: 问得好，各位。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Good questions everybody.
演讲者2: 我有一个简短的问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I have a quick question.
迈克 · 诺斯: 是的 讲者3: 所以
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So
超载签名是一种文档策略？
the overload signature's
a documentation strategy?
麦克 · 诺斯: 不，好吧-演讲者3: 看起来有点像。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: No, well-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: It seems kind of like one.
迈克 · 诺斯: 可以肯定的是，它有文档化的好处。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: It has
documentation benefits, to be sure.
因为消费者很清楚他们应该做什么。
Because it's very clear to consumers
what they should be doing.
但我只是说这不仅仅是一个文档化的策略
But I only say it's not purely
a documentation strategy
因为它实际上有类型检查分支。
because it actually has type
checking ramifications.
这个签名在72行，我的意思是，这个尝试调用这里的函数,
This signature on line 72, I mean,
this attempt to invoke the function here,
这不是类型检查，因为我们只允许 a 和 a，b 和 b。
this is not type checking because
we only allow a and a, b and b.
这里的签名是 a 和 b。
And this signature here
is trying to do a and b.
这就像是我们可以传入的一个不允许的参数范围。
It is like a disallowed range of
arguments that we can pass in.
所以不仅仅是提供有用的工具技巧,
So more than just
providing useful tool tips,
它实际上是为某些类型的祈祷开绿灯
it is actually greenlighting
certain styles of invocation and
禁止其他不合适的事情。
forbidding anything else that's not,
that doesn't fit.
迈克 · 诺斯: 这里有人用支持模式的语言工作过吗
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Has anyone here ever worked
with a language that supports pattern
比如 Scala、 Erlang 或 Elixir？
matching like Scala or Erlang or Elixir?
所以这和模式类似，你可以经常这样做
So this is similar to patterns,
where often you can
定义为特定情况设计的多个签名。
define multiple signatures that
are designed for specific cases.
这里的区别是你只能有多个函数头。
The difference here is you can
only have multiple function heads.
你不能有多个实现，对吗？
You can't have multiple implementations,
right?
但是你可以在这里有多种行为，独立的共享功能
But you can have multiple behaviors here,
independent functions that share
同样的名字，叠在一起，只有签名。
the same name and kind of stack on top
of each other, just the signatures.
原因是这必须成为 JavaScript。
And the reason is this
has to become JavaScript.
这个 JavaScript 不支持这种模式。
And this JavaScript doesn't
support patterns in that way.
但我也是这么想的。
But I think of it in similar way.